Guide to the Scottie Fitzgerald Smith Papers, 1858-1996 (bulk 1921-1986)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series II. Biography —Recordings
  - Interviews with others about FSFLS
    - JUNE 1987 TRIP TO ALABAMA
      - Lunch at Elite with Dodgie, Dot Moore, and Henrietta McGuire about FSFLS's political work (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (46:46) (Box 11 - CD 37 (Tape 24 side b))
      - Browning, George Alfred and Dodgie Shaffer — much about Browning's experiences in WWII (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (47:01) (Box 11 - CD 38 (Tape 25 side a))
      - Browning, George Alfred and Dodgie Shaffer — much about Browning's experiences in WWII (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (33:41) (Box 11 - CD 39 (Tape 25 side b))
      - Party thrown by Dot Moore in Montgomery, includes reminiscences by several people about FSFLS's political work and life in Montgomery, 24 June 1987; (46:56) (Box 11 - CD 40 (Tape 26))
      - Browning, George Alfred — Much about his military career and moves, but somewhere around minute 25, he starts talking about Scottie (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), 1987?; (46:59 - poor recording - bad sound and high speed) (Box 11 - CD 41 (Tape 27))
    - OCTOBER 1992 TRIP TO ALABAMA
      - Browning, George Alfred — a few minutes about the last few days of FSFLS's life (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), October 1992; (3:37) (Box 11 - CD 42 (Tape 28))
      - Shaffer, Dodgie and John and Eddie Pattillo — Eleanor Lanahan's relationship with FSFLS, the process of writing Scottie, the Daughter of, the Montgomery Sayre house, and FSFLS's issues with intimacy (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), October 1992; (55:29 - false starts until 8:38) (Box 11 - CD 43 (Tape 29))
      - Shaffer, Dodgie and John and Eddie Pattillo — FSFLS's feelings about entertaining (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), October 1992; (7:17) (Box 11 - CD 44 (Tape 29))
      - Shaffer, Dodgie and John and Eddie Pattillo — Tim Lanahan's death (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), October 1992; (9:08) (Box 11 - CD 45 (Tape 30))
      - Moore, Dot, Nancy Grisham Anderson, and Wayne Greenhaw — talk in a car about Selma, Alabama and Anderson's NEH-funded educational work (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), October 1992; (14:01) (Box 11 - CD 46 (Tape 31 side b))
      - Nancy Grisham Anderson and Dot Moore speak at the induction of Zelda Fitzgerald and FSFLS into the Alabama Women's Hall of Fame, October 1992; (minutes 1-20) (Box 11 - CD 47 (Tape 31 side a))
      - ??? — about trip to Europe in 1979 (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), October 1992; (minutes 20-22) (Box 11 - CD 47 (Tape 31 side a))
    - OTHERS ALPHABETICALLY
      - Bruccoli, Matthew — Bruccoli's involvement with Nancy Milford's book and other works about Zelda Fitzgerald, as well as his general working relationship with FSFLS (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), 10 February 1988; (32:16 and 5:12 - phone interview) (Box 11 - CD 48 (Tape 32))
      - Carpenter, Liz — First 8 minutes include primarily Eleanor's memories, the rest is about FSFLS's political activities (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), 7 August 1987; (18:22 and 2:49) (Box 11 - CD 49 (Tape 33))
      - Carusi, Ceci and Mary Chewning —FSFLS's political activities (including the 1964 caravan), her travels, relationship with France and the rest of Europe, and privacy issues (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), circa 1987; (47:09) (Box 11 - CD 50 (Tape 34 side a))
      - Carusi, Ceci and Mary Chewning —FSFLS's MS fund-raising work, her marriages, her cancer, and various aspects of her personality (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), circa 1987; (47:12) (Box 11 - CD 51 (Tape 34 side b))
      - Carusi, Ceci and Mary Janney — about FSFLS's political work, Trapeze, and George Alfred Browning (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), undated; (38:17) (Box 11 - CD 52 (Tape 35))
      - Chewning, Mary — how FSFLS discussed her childhood (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), 1994; (Track 1, minutes 1-8 - phone interview) (Box 12 - CD 67 (Tape 47))
      - Devron, Howard — FSFLS's musical works (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), September 1987; (31:16 and Minutes 1-19 of track 2 - phone interview ) (Box 11 - CD 53 (Tape 36))
      - Durr, Virginia — FSFLS's political work in Alabama and the friendships she formed there (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), 2 August 1987; (32:12 and 0:47 - phone interview) (Box 12 - CD 54 (Tape 37))
      - Fritchey, Clayton — Washington journalism and politics, and his relationship with FSFLS (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), [8 April 1987]; (41:33) (Box 12 - CD 55 (Tape 38 side b))
      - Gardner, Joan — friendship with FSFLS and FSFLS's marriage to Grove Smith (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), undated; (22:57) (Box 12 - CD 56 (Tape 38 side a))
      - Gardner, Joan and Arthur — family events and the Washington social scene (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), [April 1987]; (45:01) (Box 12 - CD 57 (Tape 43 side a))
      - Hazard, Blake — the process of writing Scottie, and some family business (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), 1994; (Track 1, minutes 12-20 - phone interview) (Box 12 - CD 67 (Tape 47))
      - Janney, Mary — FSFLS's time at Vassar, their continuing friendship, and FSFLS's marriages (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), undated; (46:45 and 15:11 — recording grows poor around minute 40 of track 1) (Box 12 - CD 58 (Tape 39))
      - Kerr, Joan Paterson — how FSFLS discussed her childhood (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), 1994; (Track 1, minutes 8-12 - phone interview) (Box 12 - CD 67 (Tape 47))
      - Kurth, Peter — the focus of the FSFLS biography and the process of getting it written and published (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), undated; (14:40 and 29:01) (Box 12 - CD 59 (Tape 40))
      - McConihe, Margo — MS musicals as well as FSFLS's marriages and relationships with Clayton Fritchey and George Alfred Browning (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), July 1987; (47:11) (Box 12 - CD 60 (Tape 41 side a))
      - McConihe, Margo — MS musicals as well as FSFLS's marriages and relationships with Clayton Fritchey and George Alfred Browning (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), July 1987; (9:51) (Box 12 - CD 61 (Tape 41 side b))
      - Means, Marianne — the Northern Virginia Sun, Washington politics, FSFLS's writing, Sheila Graham, and Clayton Fritchey (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), 8 April 1987; (31:17 and 31:17 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 12 - CD 62 (Tape 42))
      - Means, Marianne — journalism and writing, and FSFLS's relationships with George Alfred Browning and Clayton Fritchey (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), [8 April 1987]; (21:36 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 12 - CD 63 (Tape 43 side b))
      - Ross, Janet — how she first met FSFLS, and their later relationship as in-laws, and life in Nonquitt (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), July 1987; (45:58 and 10:55) (Box 12 - CD 64 (Tape 44))
      - Shepherd, Peter — the making of the 1974 film version of The Great Gatsby, as well as other publishing issues relating to her own work and that of her parents (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), 25 January 1988; (31:49 and 31:46 - phone interview) (Box 12 - CD 65 (Tape 45))
      - Weaver, Peanut and Jeff —Tim Lanahan's life before his suicide (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), October 1992; (Track 1 - 31:21 phone interview) (Box 12 - CD 66 (Tape 46 side a))
      - Weaver, Seabury —Tim Lanahan's life before his suicide (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), October 1992; (Track 2 - 31:22 - phone interview) (Box 12 - CD 66 (Tape 46 side b))
      - Wolff, Geoffrey — discussion between Eleanor and Wolff about F. Scott Fitzgerald at a dinner party in the mid 1960s at Gene Tunney's (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), 10 February 1994; (Track 2 - 8:09 - phone interview) (Box 12 - CD 67 (Tape 47))
- Series III. School Notebooks
  - "Calcul" notebook, 1937; (1 volume) (Folder 1.38)
  - "Dicteés" notebooks, circa 1930s; (2 volumes) (Folder 1.39)
  - "Narrations" notebooks, circa 1930s; (7 volumes) (Folders 1.40 - 1.41)
  - "Science" notebook, circa 1930s; (1 volume) (Folder 1.42)
- Series IV. Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - Browning, Col. George A., 17 Aug [no year]; (1 ALS) (Folder 1.43)
    - Bruccoli, Matthew, 1967, undated; (3 carbons, 1 frag) (Folder 1.44)
    - Curtis, Charlotte (New York Times), circa 1965-1966; (1 draft, 1 carbon) (Folder 1.45)
    - Demoncy Colette (babysitter), 21 Nov [no year]; (1 ALS) (Folder 1.46)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, 1925, undated; (2 postcards) (Folder 1.47)
    - Fitzgerald, Zelda, 1930-1931; (4 ALS, 4 postcards) (Folder 1.48)
    - Fritchey, Clayton, 20 Mar 1966; (1 draft) (Folder 1.49)
    - Gardner, Joan, 1969, undated; (1 TLS, 1 ALS, 1 carbon) (Folder 1.50)
    - Hazard, Blake, Nathan and Zachary, circa 1978-1985; (2 greeting cards, 3 ALS) (Folder 1.51)
    - Hazard, Rowley, 1973-1984; (6 ALS, 2 TLS) (Folder 1.52)
    - Hill, Elizabeth, 1973; (1 postcard) (Folder 1.53)
    - [Kroll?], Nathan and Frances, 12 Mar [no year]; (1 carbon) (Folder 1.54)
    - Lanahan, Eleanor, 1962-1969; (6 folders) (Folders 1.55 - 1.60)
    - Lanahan, Eleanor, 1970-1981; (8 folders) (Folders 2.1 - 2.8)
    - Lanahan, Eleanor, 1983-1985; (2 folders) (Folders 2.9 - 2.10)
    - Lanahan, Eleanor, undated; (1 folder) (Folder 2.11)
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jack,", [1940], 1944-1945, 1957, 1963-1975, 1985; (2 folders) (Folders 2.12 - 2.13)
    - [Lanahan Family Correspondence], circa 1966-1971; [RESTRICTED] (Box 24)
    - [Lanahan Family Correspondence], 1983-1986; [RESTRICTED] (Box 24)
    - Lanahan, Sheila, 1 Jan 1971; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.14)
    - Lanahan/Smith children, 17 Nov 1967; (1 TL) (Folder 2.15)
    - McAdoo, Cynthia, 1945-1951; (5 ALS) (Folder 2.16)
    - McAdoo, Francis, circa 1940s; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.17)
    - McCarthy, Eugene, 17 Sep 1968; (1 carbon) (Folder 2.18)
    - Miles, Eleanor Lanahan, 1942-1943, 1978-1986; (7 ALS, 3 TLS) (Folder 2.19)
    - Mayfield, Sara, circa 1971; (1 carbon) (Folder 2.20)
    - Ober, Anne, 20 Jan 1958; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.21)
    - Ridder, Walter, undated; (photocopy) (Folder 2.22)
    - Sayre, Minerva, 1927-1930, undated; (14 ALS, 3 postcards) (Folder 2.23)
    - Smith, C. Grove, 1979-1985, undated; (8 TLS, 5 ALS, 1 carbon (Folder 2.24)
    - Smith, Rosalind Sayre, 17 Apr [1931]; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.25)
    - "Santa,", circa 1920s; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.26)
    - "Jacqueline,", circa 1920s; (unsent postcard) (Folder 2.27)
    - "Dorothy, " re: F. Scott Fitzgerald's "Lo, the Poor Peacock" as printed in Esquire, [1971]; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.28)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Folder 2.29)
  - Incoming
    - Baker, Clotilde, 6 Mar 1986; (1 ALS - 2 photographs separated) (Folder 2.30)
    - [Baldridge, Letitia?], [1962?]; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.31)
    - Boggs, Lindy, 22 July 1976; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.32)
    - [Bourjaily], Vance, 9 Oct 1965; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.33)
    - Bradlee, Ben (Washington Post), 16 May 1966; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.34)
    - Brady, James W. (Women's Wear Daily), 1 Mar 1966; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.35)
    - Brinson, Marjorie Sayre, 1943-1949; (2 TLS, 2 ALS) (Folder 2.36)
    - Bruccoli, Matthew, 1969-1986, undated; (5 TLS, 1 ALS, enclosures) (Folder 4.17)
    - Carpenter, Liz, 1978, 1986; (2 postcards) (Folder 2.37)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 10 Nov 1975, undated; (1 TLS, 1 Christmas card) (Folder 2.38)
    - Cerf, Bennett (Random House), 1945; (3 TLS and 1 enclosure) (Folder 2.39)
    - Church, Frank, 1959, 1973, 1976; (3 TLS) (Folder 2.40)
    - Curtis, Charlotte (New York Times), 1965-1966; (3 TLS) (Folder 2.41)
    - Davis, Meyer, 4 Jan 1966; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.42)
    - de Havilland, Olivia, 9 July 1981; (1 ALS) (Folder 4.18)
    - Delihant, Thomas, 1945-1947, undated; (3 TLS, 1 ALS) (Folder 2.43)
    - Donaldson, Scott, 20 July 1978; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.44)
    - Fitzgerald, Mollie McQuillan, 1928, undated; (6 ALS) (Folder 2.45)
    - Fitzgerald, Zelda, 1928; (1 postcard) (Folder 3.76)
    - Fox, Evelyn K. (Woman's Club of Rockville), 1975-1976; (4 TLS) (Folder 2.46)
    - Fulbright, J. William, 26 July 1974; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.47)
    - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1962, 1963; (2 autographed notes and annotated articles) (Folder 2.48)
    - Gill, Brendan (The New Yorker), circa 1945-1946, 1951, 1972, undated; (4 TLS, 2 ALS, 1 note (Folder 2.49)
    - Gingrich, Arnold (Esquire), 13 Sep 1961; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.50)
    - Goodhue, Mary "Dede,", 16 June 1986; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.51)
    - Graeber, Betty Beale, 7 Feb 1984; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.52)
    - Graham, Katharine (Washington Post), 1967-1970; (2 TLS, 1 ALS) (Folder 2.53)
    - Graham, Sheilah, 29 Mar 1951; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.54)
    - Harrison, Gilbert A., 26 Jan 1976; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.55)
    - Hart, Gary, 25 Aug 1982; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.56)
    - Hayes, Harold (Esquire), 15 July 1965; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.57)
    - Hersey, John (Life Magazine), 10 Mar 1944; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.58)
    - Highland Hospital (re Zelda Fitzgerald), 1947, 1948; (2 TLS) (Folder 2.59)
    - Hoopes, Townsend "Tim,", 1953-1957, undated; (6 ALS, 2 TLS) (Folder 2.60)
    - Humphrey, Muriel, 29 Sep 1968; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.61)
    - Janney, Mary, 6 July 1967; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.62)
    - Johnson, Lady Bird, 1964, 1982, 1986; (2 TLS, 1 telegram) (Folder 2.63)
    - Johnson, Lady Bird — See also, Biography — Funeral Attendance book, for June 1986 telegram
    - [Kidder, Frances Turnbull?], circa 1975, 18 June 1986; (2 ALS, 2 photographs separated) (Folder 2.64)
    - Ladies Home Journal, 24 Apr 1941; (1 TLS, 1 typed note) (Folder 2.65)
    - Lanahan, Betty, 31 Jan 1947; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.66)
    - Lanahan, Cecilia, circa 1967; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.67)
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jack", 22 Jan 1940; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.68)
    - Lanahan, William Wallace, circa 1946; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.69)
    - MacRae, [?] (re Zelda Fitzgerald), circa 1948; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.70)
    - Marshman, D. M. (Donald M. "Mac"), 1945-1946; (2 ALS) (Folder 2.71)
    - Mayfield, Sara, 1970-1971; (1 TLS, 2 forwarded TLS re Zelda Fitzgerald) (Folder 2.72)
    - McCarthy, Eugene, 19 Oct 1968; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.73)
    - McGovern, George, 6 Feb 1973; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.74)
    - Menotti, Gian Carlo, 21 Jan 1976; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.75)
    - Miles, Eleanor Lanahan, 1947-1967, 1979; (3 ALS, 1 TLS) (Folder 2.76)
    - Mondale, Walter, 9 Feb 1984; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.77)
    - Morris, Willie, 15 Sep 1976; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.78)
    - Muskie, Edmund and Jane, 1971-1972; (3 TLS) (Folder 2.79)
    - Myers, Carmel, 20 Nov 1970; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.80)
    - Naylor, Lawrence P., 1939-1940; (2 ALS) (Folder 2.81)
    - New York City League of Women Voters, 6 Oct 1944; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.82)
    - Newman, Harry Wright, 21 Dec 1982; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.83)
    - Noyes, Newbold (Washington Evening Star), 23 Feb 1966; (1 TLS with FSFLS's notes) (Folder 2.84)
    - Ober, Anne, 12 Oct 1938; (1 TL) (Folder 2.85)
    - Palmer, Clothilde Sayre, 3 Jan 1946; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.86)
    - Pattillo, Edward "Eddie,", 1983-1986; (1 TLS, 1 ALS, 6 postcards) (Folder 2.87)
    - Perkins, Maxwell, 1943, 1945; (2 TLS) (Folder 2.88)
    - Prince, Harold, 5 June 1980; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.89)
    - Ransom, Louise, 1973, 1986; (1 ALS, 2 TLS) (Folder 2.90)
    - Ring, Frances, 15 Sep 1981; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.91)
    - Robb, Lynda Bird Johnson, Sep 1977; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.92)
    - Sayre, Minerva, 1927-1929; (12 ALS) (Folder 4.19)
    - Sayre, Minerva, 1946-1953, undated; (14 ALS, 1 frag) (Folder 4.20)
    - Seldes, Timothy (Harcourt Brace), 7 Jan 1966; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.93)
    - Sereze, V., 26 Oct 1931; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.94)
    - Scribner, Charles, 1979, 1981; (1 ALS, 1 annotated clipping) (Folder 2.95)
    - Shriver, Sargent, 12 Sep 1975; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.96)
    - Smith, Jacqueline "Poupette,", 1986; (3 postcards, 1 greeting card) (Folder 2.97)
    - Smith, Rosalind Sayre, 1945-1976, undated; (7 TLS, 2 ALS, TLS from lawyer to nursing home) (Folder 4.21)
    - Sprague, Annabel Fitzgerald, 1974-1975; (2 ALS) (Folder 2.98)
    - Stevenson, Adlai, 1962-1963; (3 TLS, 1 TL) (Folder 2.99)
    - Tidyman, Ernest (New York Times), 23 Feb 1966; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.100)
    - Vaughn, Courtney Sprague (Annabel Fitzgerald Sprague's daughter), 1978, undated; (2 ALS) (Folder 2.101)
    - Weaver, Peanut, 11 May 1960; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.102)
    - White, Theodore: See Politics — Notes on McGovern Campaign
    - Williams, Tennessee, 12 May 1962; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.103)
    - [Winship?], Tom, 17 Dec 1965; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.104)
    - Wouk, Herman, 5 Apr 1974; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.105)
    - Yates, Janty and Paul Martin Smith, 1978, 1984, 1986; (2 ALS, 1 telegram) (Folder 4.22)
    - "Nannie Eva,", circa 1920s; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.106)
    - Miscellaneous letters in French, circa 1920s; (2 ALS, 2 postcards) (Folder 2.107)
    - "Bobby" (college boyfriend), 7 Dec 1939; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.108)
    - "Brad" (college boyfriend), Feb 1939; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.109)
    - "Jim" (college boyfriend), 20 Feb 1939; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.110)
    - "Stanley" (college boyfriend), 11 Oct 1939; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.111)
    - "Sally,", undated; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.112)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1928-1986 (Folder 2.113)
  - From Others to Others
    - Bruccoli, Matthew to Eleanor Lanahan, 1983, 1986; (3 TLS, 1 note) (Folder 2.114)
    - Ethel Walker School to F. Scott Fitzgerald, 11 June 1938; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.115)
    - Ethel Walker School to Anne Ober, Oct-Nov 1936; (2 TLS, 2 notices) (Folder 2.116)
    - Fischer, Elizabeth to Eleanor Lanahan, 1986; (4 TLS) (Folder 2.117)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott to "Mme. White" about FSFLS, addressed from Grove Park Inn, Ashville, North Carolina, [1936]; [See Autograph Files ]
    - Fitzgerald, John to F. Scott Fitzgerald, Oct 1909; (1 postcard) (Folder 2.118)
    - Hardesty, Emily to Eleanor Lanahan, 1986; (2 ALS, 1 TLS from an attorney) (Folder 2.119)
    - Janney, Mary D. to Eleanor Lanahan, 1986; (1 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 copy of FSFLS eulogy) (Folder 2.120)
    - Kiefer, Kitty to Eleanor Lanahan, 13 Aug 1979; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.121)
    - Lanahan, Betty to Eleanor Lanahan, undated; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.122)
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky" to Eleanor Lanahan, circa 1986; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.123)
    - Lanahan, William Wallace to Jack Lanahan, 1945; (2 TLS, 1 carbon) (Folder 2.124)
    - Lanahan, Wallace to William Wallace and Eleanor Lanahan, circa 1940s; (1 ALS, 1 TLS) (Folder 2.125)
    - Meyer, Starke to Eleanor Lanahan, 1986; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.126)
    - Miles, Eleanor Lanahan to Eleanor Lanahan, 1986, 1988; (2 ALS, 1 TLS) (Folder 2.127)
    - Miles, Eleanor Lanahan to Jack Lanahan, 1945-1946, undated; (7 ALS, 5 TLS) (Folder 2.128)
    - Ober, Richard to Eleanor Lanahan, 18 Feb 1987; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.129)
    - Pier, Arthur S. and Andre Brewster to William Wallace and Eleanor Lanahan (re Tim Lanahan), circa 1940s; (2 carbons) (Folder 2.130)
    - Raimey, Josephine to Minerva Sayre (re Zelda Fitzgerald), 1948; (2 ALS) (Folder 2.131)
    - Sayre, Minerva to Zelda Fitzgerald, 11 May 1928; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.132)
    - Sayre, Minerva to [Smith?] Newman, 9 Dec 1950; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.133)
    - Sayre, Minerva to "Jacques,", 26 May 1955; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.134)
    - Smith, Jacqueline "Poupette" to Eleanor and Cecilia Lanahan, 1986-1987; (2 ALS) (Folder 2.135)
    - Smith, Rosalind Sayre to Jack Lanahan, 14 Feb 1951; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.136)
    - Sprague, Annabel Fitzgerald to Zelda Fitzgerald, undated; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.137)
    - Summers, U. T. to Eleanor Lanahan, 21 Sep 1988; (1 TLS) (Folder 2.138)
    - Weaver, Peanut to Jack Lanahan, circa 1960s; (1 ALS) (Folder 2.139)
    - Condolence letters to the Lanahan children, A-M, 1986; (2 folders) (Folders 2.140 - 2.141)
    - Condolence letters to the Lanahan children, N-Z, unidentified, 1986; (2 folders) (Folders 3.1-3.2)
  - Invitations
    - Misc invitations to FSFLS (Folder 3.3)
    - Misc invitations from FSFLS (Folder 3.4)
- Series V. Writings
  - "Doings of a Bad Girl, or a Consequence of Algebra,", 1935 (Folder 3.5)
  - "A Short Retort," Mademoiselle, July 1939 (Folder 3.6)
  - "End of Everything," College Bazaar, Aug 1940 (Folder 4.23)
  - Time, Inc. news broadcasts, circa 1942-1943 (Folder 3.7)
  - "Book Jacket, 1945," Saturday Review of Literature, 5 May 1945 (Folder 3.8)
  - "The Water Cooler," The New Yorker, 22 Sep 1945 (Folder 3.9)
  - "New Yorker Story, 1945," Saturday Review of Literature, 13 Oct 1945 (Folder 3.10)
  - "The Importance of Being Kissed," Colliers, 23 Feb 1946; (clipping) (Folder 3.11)
  - "The Importance of Being Kissed," Colliers, 23 Feb 1946; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - "Table for Two" columns and book reviews, The New Yorker, 1946-1948; (typescripts and galley proofs) (Folder 3.12)
  - "Table for Two" columns and book reviews, The New Yorker, circa 1945-1948; (clippings) (Folder 4.24)
  - "How They Started," Junior Bazaar, Apr 1947 (Folder 4.25)
  - Unidentified article, Junior Bazaar, Sep 1947 (Folder 4.26)
  - "The Stocking Present," The New Yorker, 27 Dec 1947 (Folder 4.27)
  - "Cinderella's Daughter,", 1952; (2 drafts and correspondence) (Folder 3.13)
  - Democratic Digest, 1954-1955; (published pieces) (Folder 3.14)
  - Democratic Digest, 1956, undated; (typescripts) (Folder 4.28)
  - Original water colors from Democratic Digest covers, circa 1954; (2 water colors) (Folder 23.8)
  - "Cupid and Psyche,", 1956 (Folder 3.15)
  - Northern Virginia Sun articles — scrapbooks, 1957-1958; (3 volumes) (Boxes 25-26)
  - Northern Virginia Sun articles, circa 1957-1959; (4 folders of loose clippings) (Folders 4.29 - 4.32)
  - "Fitzgerald As He Really Was," book review, Washington Post, 27 Apr 1958 (Folder 4.33)
  - Toast to Phyllis Fritchey on the eve of her wedding, [23 May 1958] (Folder 3.16)
  - "'Little Rhody' Revels in Triple Play at Polls," Washington Post, 26 June 1960 (Folder 4.34)
  - "3 Rhode Island Democrats Vie for Green's Senate Seat," Washington Post, 27 Sep 1960 (Folder 4.35)
  - "A Fascinating Place to Live," House and Garden, July 1962; (clipping) (Folder 4.36)
  - "A Fascinating Place to Live," House and Garden, July 1962; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - "The Political Woman: Two Phases," Esquire, July 1962; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - "The Night Before Congress," Washington Post, 6 Jan 1963 (Folder 4.37)
  - Articles about the Peace Corps, Washington Post, June 1963 (Folder 4.38)
  - "Merry Christmas from the Smiths," The New Yorker, 21 Dec 1963 (Folder 3.17)
  - "The Lovely Americans" — piece for Esquire on the Peace Corps, circa 1963 (Folder 3.18)
  - Letter to the Editor of the Evening Star, 1 Feb 1964 (Folder 3.19)
  - The Cat's Whiskers / Love, Among Other Things — Drafts, 1964; (2 folders) (Folder 3.20 - 3.21)
  - The Cat's Whiskers / Love, Among Other Things — Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Folder 3.22)
  - The Cat's Whiskers / Love, Among Other Things — Auburn University production, 1988 (Folder 4.39)
  - "Interior Analysis,", 31 Oct 1965 (Folder 4.40)
  - "My Father's Letters: Advice Without Consent," Esquire, Oct 1965; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - "Time with Tonsein,", 1965 (Folder 3.23)
  - New York Times articles, 1965-1966 (Folder 4.41)
  - New York Times articles — check stubs, 1965-1966 (Folder 4.42)
  - "War Declared on Affluence," Evening Post News [satirical MS mock newspaper, 4 March 1966 (Folder 6.2)
  - "Beauty and the Hairdresser," Washington Post Potomac, 26 June 1966 (Folder 3.24)
  - "Paradise for Plain and Prancing," Lancaster New Era, Sep 1966; (article and responses) (Folder 5.44)
  - "A Place Where People Really Live," House and Garden, Oct 1966; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - "News to Me" column, Washington Post, 1966-1967; (scrapbooks of original clippings - 2 volumes) (Boxes 27-28)